# Shubham Maini

A: Melbourne, Australia T:0450778603 E: shubhammaini112@gmail.com LinkedIn Profile:

www.linkedin.com/in/shubham-maini-980434191

# **Career Summary**

An Enthusiastic Graduate who completed a Master of Information and Communication and Technology coming up with proven practical experience with Modern Technologies like Nodejs and React. influenced software developer with 1+ years of experience with a cross-functional agile team environment and strong leadership skills looking to serve in the organization to demonstrate the ability to work independently as well as in a team that is going to add up value to your organization. I have a strong ability to exercise judgement in a complex environment.

## **Technical Skills**

Front-End Development: React, HTML, CSS3

**Back-End Development:** PHP, Node JS, C++

**Database and Tools:** MySQL, MongoDB, Visual Studio Code, FileZilla, Postman,

PostgreSQL

Cloud Computing: Amazon Web Services, S3, AWS Face recognition, C#,Net

#### **Education**

**Professional Year**Performance Education, City

Apr 2020 - Current

Key Subjects: Australian Business Culture and Environment, Achieving Career Success, Australian Workplace Skills and Professional Business Communication

**Master of Information and Communication Technology** 

March 2020-Nov 2021

University of Sunshine Coast, Melbourne, Australia Special interest in Software Development

**Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering** 

**Apr 2013 - Jun 2017** 

Punjab Technical University, Punjab, India

Key learning areas included: OOPS, RDBMS, Web Development

# **University Project**

## **Emergency Management**

July 2021 - Oct 2021

University of Sunshine Coast, Melbourne, Australia

**Objective:** The goal of the project was to build an automated system of health management system

using AWS face recognition latest cloud API which was highly focused on saving the

health of an individual when an injury has occurred.

**Tools:** A waterfall method is effectively used in this project which is efficiently managed with

the latest tool called Jira.

**Duties:** A group project in which as a team leader I am responsible for time management and

fully accountable for connecting a Back-end with a front-end which ends up with an interactive user interface. I was also responsible for committing the code to GitHub and fixing the bugs and encouraging teammates who do not belong to a programming

background which adds up their new skills.

**Outcome:** we end up with a smooth-running hybrid app that is ready to use in the market to

promote the health management system which we completed by the given deadline.

**Result:** Obtained High Distinction

**View Projects** 

# **Employment History**

#### **Backend Developer**

Sep 2018 – Mar 2020

Wegile Technologies, Punjab, Mohali

#### **Duties:**

- Created APIs (frontend connectivity) using tools such as Postman, Visual Studio
- Effectively managed stakeholders and participated in meetings to make them understand the functionality of workflows
- Fixed bugs and server issues in the backend to ensure a seamless user experience

- Built strong communication with colleagues to bestow the user data efficiently
- Effectively used the Linux-based operating system to deploy the backend services to the server

# Victas Fright

Sep 2021 - current

Dandenong South, Victoria, Australia

#### **Duties:**

- Perform hand sorting of Mailbags into cages and compartments
- Checking mails and parcels have been addressed.
- Screening the boxed and stamp a date on it.
- Validating the correct postage has been paid.
- Organize a pallet of boxes and deliver with the appropriate postcode

#### **Personal Attributes**

- Excellent creative mindset, which I possessed through my last work experience with the excellent mindset to think out of the box and serve a unique idea to solve the problem.
- As a Backend developer and team member, I worked under pressure calmly and professionally.
- Self-motivation keeps my thoughts positive especially when I was working with my teammates which helps me to keep my goals aligned.
- A flexible and encouraging nature who always collaborates and is adaptable to new environments.

#### **Hobbies and Interests**

• I like to listen to music especially old Pakistani music.

## References

Sidharth Khanna – IOS Developer - +91 9878326638